Guide to the Cass Gilbert Papers and Architectural Drawings 1883-1952 (Bulk 1900-1934) PR 21
New-York Historical Society
- Series X. Architectural Drawings, 1883-1952
  - PR21.47: Charleston Harbor Improvement and Hotel (Charleston, S.C.), 1909
    - Study (block plans). graphite and crayon on trace and board., 1909 August 5 (Object PR21.47.O1)
  - PR21.48: Charleston Hotel (Charleston, W. Va.), 1922
    - Sketch (exterior perspective). mixed media on board., 1922 September (Object PR21.48.O1)
  - PR21.49: Charleston Public Library (Charleston, W. Va.), 1924
  - PR21.50: William Chase, Iron Newel in Studio, 1881
    - Wrought iron newel post (study). ink on paper., 1881 (Object PR21.50.O1)
  - PR21.51: Chase Brass Company Building (Waterbury, Conn.), 1915-1919
    - Front elevation study. graphite and colored pencil on trace and board. (Object PR21.51.O1)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-194)
  - PR21.52: Chase Memorial Dispensary Building (Waterbury, Conn.), 1921-1923
  - PR21.53: Chi Psi Chapter House (Middlebury, Vt.), 1921
  - PR21.54: Chicago Post Office (Chicago, Ill.), 1900
  - PR21.55: Christ Church (LaCrosse, Wis.), 1897
  - PR21.56: Christ [Memorial] Episcopal Church (Hibbing, Minn.), 1896
  - PR21.57: Church on the Green (New Haven, Conn.)
  - PR21.58: A. E. Clark, Ashland Avenue House (Saint Paul, Minn.)
  - PR21.59: Clark Bryant Hotel (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1887
  - PR21.59A: C. F. Clark Office Building (Saint Paul, Minn.)
    - Rolled drawings (Offsite-box CG-194)
  - PR21.60: Odin G. Clay Building (Saint Paul, Minn.)
    - Front elevation. Vandyke or ferro gallic print on paper and board. First floor plan. Vandyke or ferro gallic print on paper and board., 1893 May 10 (Object PR21.60.O1)
  - PR21.61: Odin G. Clay Residence (Grey Cloud, Minn.)
  - PR21.62: J. M. Clayburgh House (Helena, Mont.)
  - PR21.63: Columbus Hotel (Columbus, Ohio)
  - PR21.64: Congregational Church, Parsonage (Northfield, Minn.)
  - PR21.65: Connecticut Light and Power Sub Station #2 (Waterbury, Conn.), 1903-1904, 1917
  - PR21.66: Connecticut State Library and Supreme Court (Hartford, Conn.), 1906
  - PR21.67: Mrs. Conroy House (White Bear Lake, Minn.)
  - PR21.68: Continental Bank of Chicago (Chicago, Ill.), 1902
  - PR21.68A: Continental Insurance Company Building (St. Paul, Minn.)
    - Folded drawing: alteration (Offsite-box CG-194)
  - PR21.69: Criterion Club
    - Proposed alteration, section. graphite and ink on trace and board. (Object PR21.69.O1)
    - Proposed alteration, fourth and fifth floor plans. graphite and ink on trace and board (2 drawings) (Object PR21.69.O2)
    - Proposed alteration, second and third floor plans. graphite and ink on trace and board. (2 drawings) (Object PR21.69.O3)
    - Proposed alteration, basement and first floor plans. graphite and ink on trace and board. (Object PR21.69.O4)
    - Proposed alteration, front elevation. graphite and ink on trace and board. (Object PR21.69.O5)
  - PR21.70: Cushing Department Store (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1898
  - PR21.71: Dr. William Davis, Laurel Avenue House (Saint Paul, Minn.)
  - PR21.72: Dayton Avenue Presbyterian Church (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1886-1888; 1902; 1909-1911
  - PR21.73: W. B. Dean Cottage (White Bear Lake, Minn.), 1893, 1903
  - PR21.74: W. B. Dean and J. H. Skinner, Double Barn at Manitou Island (White Bear Lake, Minn.), 1894
  - PR21.75: W. J. Dean House (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1894
  - PR21.76: John De Laittre House (Minneapolis, Minn.), 1906
  - PR21.77: Delta Kappa Epsilon House (Middlebury, Vt.), 1921 (Object PR21.77.O1)
    - Exterior perspective. colored pencil on trace and board (Object PR21.77.O1)
  - PR21.78: Delta Psi Chapter House, University of Vermont (Burlington, Vt.), 1921
  - PR21.79: Denison Train Depot (Denison, Tex.)
  - PR21.80: Department of Justice Building (Washington, D.C.)
  - PR21.81: Detroit Cultural Center (Detroit, Mich.), 1921
    - Plan of the proposed center of arts and letters for the City of Detroit. graphite on trace and board., 1915 November 29 (Object PR21.81.O1)
    - Plan of the proposed center of arts and letters for the City of Detroit. graphite on trace and board., 1915 December 9 (Object PR21.81.O2)
    - Plan of the proposed center of arts and letters for the City of Detroit. graphite on trace and board., 1915 December 3 (Object PR21.81.O3)
    - Plan of the proposed center of arts and letters for the City of Detroit. graphite on trace and board., 1915 December 10 (Object PR21.81.O4)
  - PR21.82: Detroit Public Library (Detroit, Mich.), 1913-1921
    - Front elevation. graphite and ink wash. (Object PR21.82.O1)
    - Transverse and longitudinal sections. ink on board. (Object PR21.82.O2)
    - Side elevation. ink wash and graphite on board. (Object PR21.82.O3)
    - Exterior perspective. reproduction on board. (Object PR21.82.O4)
    - Front elevation. photoreproduction on board. (Object PR21.82.O5)
    - Front elevation. graphite and ink wash on board. (Object PR21.82.O6)
    - Mezzanine floor plan. ink on board. (Object PR21.82.O7)
    - Main floor plan. ink on board. (Object PR21.82.O8)
    - Attic floor plan. ink on board. (Object PR21.82.O9)
    - Rear and side elevations. ink on board. (Object PR21.82.O10)
    - Perspective view of grand stair hall. graphite on board., 1918 November 27 (Object PR21.82.O11)
    - Front elevation. graphite and ink wash on board. (Object PR21.82.O12)
    - Floor plan. ink on paper. (Object PR21.82.O13)
    - Perspective view of entrance hall. graphite on board., 1918 October 21 (Object PR21.82.O14)
    - Exterior perspective. photoreproduction on paper. (Object PR21.82.O15)
    - Block plan. graphite and ink on board (Object PR21.82.O16)
    - Ground floor plan. ink on board. (Object PR21.82.O17)
  - PR21.83: Jacob Dittenhoffer House (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1898
  - PR21.84: Mrs. E. F. Drake House (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1893
  - PR21.85: Driscoll House (Saint Paul, Minn.)
  - PR21.86: East River Bridge (New York, N.Y.)
  - PR21.87: East River Savings Bank (New York, N.Y.), 1910
  - PR21.88: Howard N. Elmer Residence (Saint Paul, Minn.)
  - PR21.89: Endicott Building (Saint Paul, Minn.), c.1889-1891; 1916
  - PR21.90: Endicott Retail Store Building (6th and Cedar Streets, Saint Paul, Minn.), c.1901
  - PR21.91: Essex Building (6th Street, Saint Paul, Minn.), 1905
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-194)
  - PR21.92: Essex County Courthouse (Newark, N.J.), 1904
  - PR21.93: Factory and Store Building (Rochester, N.Y.)
  - PR21.94: Col. John Farrington, Tenement Row (Saint Paul, Minn.)
    - Second floor plan. ink on board. (Object PR21.94.O1)
  - PR21.95: Federal Reserve Bank of Minnesota (Minneapolis, Minn.), 1919-1924
    - Perspective study. graphite on board., 1920 May 1 (Object PR21.95.O1)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-1)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-193)
  - PR21.96: Federal Reserve Bank of New York (New York, N.Y.), 1918-1920
  - PR21.96A: 15-17 East 40th Street, alterations (New York, N.Y.)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-48)
  - PR21.97: Fifth Avenue and 40th Street Store and Office Building (New York, N.Y.), 1934
    - 40th Street elevation. graphite on trace and board. (Object PR21.97.O1)
    - Perspective study. graphite and watercolor on paper., 1934 (Object PR21.97.O2)
  - PR21.98: Fifth Avenue and 72nd Street Apartment House (New York, N.Y.), 1911
  - PR21.99: Fifth Avenue Hotel (New York, N.Y.), 1920
    - Typical floor plan. graphite on trace and board., 1908 March 6 (Object PR21.99.O1)
    - Ground floor plan. graphite on trace and board., 1908 March 6 (Object PR21.99.O2)
  - PR21.100: Fifth Avenue House (New York, N.Y.)
    - Exterior perspective study. watercolor on paper. (Object PR21.100.O1)
    - Exterior perspective study. ink and watercolor on board., 1929 (Object PR21.100.O2)
  - PR21.101: George R. Finch, Summit Avenue House (Saint Paul, Minn.)
    - Library mantel (elevation). ink and watercolor on paper. (Object PR21.101.O1)
  - PR21.102: Fireman's Insurance Building (Newark, N.J.)
    - Exterior perspective. watercolor on board. (Object PR21.102.O1)
  - PR21.103: First Division Monument (Washington, D.C.), 1921-1924
    - Perspective study. colored pencil on board. (Object PR21.103.O1)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-193)
  - PR21.104: First German Methodist Episcopal Society Church (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1892-1894
  - PR21.105: First National Bank (Saint Louis, Mo.), 1919
    see also: Saint Louis Trust
    - Front elevation. graphite and ink wash., 1919 August 6 (Object PR21.105.O1)
  - PR21.106: First Presbyterian Church (Austin, Minn.)
  - PR21.107: First Presbyterian Church (Lincoln and Grotto Streets, Saint Paul, Minn.), 1890
  - PR21.108: Fletcher Building (Indianapolis, Ind.), 1910
    - First floor plan. ink on board., 1910 December (Object PR21.108.O1)
    - Basement plan. ink on board, 1910 December (Object PR21.108.O2)
    - Exterior perspective. mixed media on board., 1911 (Object PR21.108.O3)
    - Front elevation "Office Building". graphite on trace and board with reproduction on paper. (Object PR21.108.O4)
  - PR21.109: Floranda Club (Fort Lauderdale, Fla.), 1925
  - PR21.110: Foley Square Project (New York, N.Y.)
  - PR21.111: 43rd Street and Madison Avenue Hotel (New York, N.Y.)
  - PR21.112: Fourth Avenue and 18th Street Office Building (New York, N.Y.), 1909; 1912
  - PR21.113: Fourth Avenue and 21st Street Office Building (New York, N.Y.), 1908
  - PR21.114: Fox Department Store (Hartford, Conn.), 1917-1918
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-194)
  - PR21.115: G. W. Freeman, Summit Avenue House (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1896-1897
    - Billiard room. watercolor on paper. (Object PR21.115.O1)
  - PR21.116: Mr. J. M. Fuller Cottage (Lake Minnetonka, Minn.)
  - PR21.117: R. B. Galusha, Cottage Park Houses (White Bear Lake, Minn.)
    - Study for Road Front of House, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan. watercolor and ink on board. (Item PR21.117.O1)
  - PR21.118: R. B. Galusha, Iglehart Street Row Houses (Saint Paul, Minn.)
  - PR21.119: General Electric Project (Augusta, Ga.), 1920
  - PR21.120: George Junior Republic, Buildings (Litchfield, Conn.), 1915-1916
  - PR21.121: George Washington Bridge [Hudson River Bridge] (New York, N.Y.), 1931
    see also: Riverside Drive
    - Study for the Hudson River Bridge. graphite on trace and board., 1926 (Object PR21.121.O1)
    - Study for the Hudson River Bridge. graphite on trace and board., 1926 July 5 (Object PR21.121.O2)
    - Study showing approach and statuary. graphite and charcoal on paper and board., 1926 July (Object PR21.121.O3)
    - Study - Hudson River Bridge. graphite on paper and board., 1926 February 10 (Object PR21.121.O4)
    - Study - Hudson River Bridge. graphite on paper and board., 1926 February 12 (Object PR21.121.O5)
    - N.Y. approach foot bridge study. graphite on board., 1930 September 12 (Object PR21.121.O6)
    - Study - Hudson River Bridge. ink on paper and board., 1926 February 13 (Object PR21.121.O7)
    - Toll gate, study A. watercolor on board., 1931 (Object PR21.121.O8)
    - Toll gate, study B. watercolor on board., 1931 March 11 (Object PR21.121.O9)
    - Field office, New Jersey plaza (perspective study). watercolor on trace and board. (Object PR21.121.O10)
    - Study by Radberg after Mr. Gilbert's sketch. charcoal on paper., 1926 July (Object PR21.121.O11)
    - Field office, New Jersey plaza (perspective study). mixed media on board, 1931 March 7 (Object PR21.121.O12)
    - Elevation of floodlighting tower. graphite and watercolor on board. (Object PR21.121.O13)
    - Bird's-eye view study. graphite on paper, hinged to board., 1927 (Object PR21.121.O14)
    - First scale study for Hudson River Bridge. mixed media on board., 1926 January 15 (Object PR21.121.O15)
    - Bird's-eye view of Manhattan approach. paint on photographic print and board., 1929 (Object PR21.121.O16)
  - PR21.122: German Methodist Church (Saint Paul, Minn.)
  - PR21.123: German Bethlehem Presbyterian Church, (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1906
    - Rolled drawings (Offsite-box CG-2)
  - PR21.124: Cass Gilbert "Cannonball House", Barn, Garden, Gardener's House (Ridgefield, Conn.)
  - PR21.125: Cass Gilbert, 11 East 24th Street Office ( New York, N.Y.)
  - PR21.126: Cass Gilbert, Endicott Building Offices (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1891
  - PR21.127: Cass Gilbert, 42 East 64th Street House (New York, N.Y.)
  - PR21.128: Cass Gilbert, Metropolitan Building Annex Office (Minneapolis, Minn.)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-15)
  - PR21.129: Cass Gilbert, Office Building on Gilbert Estate
    - Plan of second story. graphite and watercolor on trace and board., 1896 July 24 (Object PR21.129.O1)
  - PR21.130: Cass Gilbert, 1 East 94th Street House (New York, N.Y.), 1925-1926
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-38)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-192)
  - PR21.131: Cass Gilbert, 38th Street and Madison Avenue Offices (New York, N.Y.), 1916-1925
  - PR21.132: Cass Gilbert Residence (Minnesota)
  - PR21.133: Cass Gilbert, Tenement Houses (Saint Paul, Minn.)
  - PR21.134: Cass and Julia Gilbert, 71 Floral Street House (Saint Paul, Minn.)
  - PR21.135: E. W. Gilbert, 470 Ashland Avenue House (Saint Paul, Minn.)
  - PR21.136: S. W. Glazier House (West End, N.J.), 1901
  - PR21.137: Golden Rule Building Addition, Robert Street (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1896
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-192)
  - PR21.138: Goodrich Avenue Presbyterian Church (Saint Paul, Minn.)
  - PR21.139: C. Gotzian & Co. Building (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1892
  - PR21.140: Paul Gotzian Residence (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1901
  - PR21.141: Grand Island Bridge (Grand Island, N.Y.), 1930
  - PR21.142: J. N. Granger, Lodge (White Bear Lake, Minn.)
  - PR21.143: Great Northern Pacific Railroad, Depot (Anoka, Minn.), 1891
  - PR21.144: Great Northern Pacific Railroad, Depot (Willmar, Minn.), 1891
  - PR21.145: Guaranty Trust Company Building (New York, N.Y.)
  - PR21.146: Guild House (Faribault, Minn.)
  - PR21.147: Emerson Hadley House (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1895
  - PR21.148: Mrs. W. S. Hall, Pleasant Avenue Residence (Saint Paul, Minn.)
  - PR21.149: Hall of the Chancellors (New York, N.Y.)
  - PR21.150: Hamilton County Courthouse
  - PR21.151: Harvard University Medical College
  - PR21.152: Hayes House (Eau Claire, Wis.)
  - PR21.153: Henry Hudson Bridge (New York, N.Y.), 1928
    - "Hendrick Hudson Memorial Bridge" bird's-eye view. watercolor on paper, 1928 August 7 (Object PR21.153.O1)
    - "Hendrick Hudson Memorial Bridge" perspective study. graphite and watercolor on board., 1928 (Object PR21.153.O2)
  - PR21.154: Herald Square Building (New York, N.Y.), 1921
    - Perspective study. graphite on paper., 1919 November 26 (Object PR21.154.O1)
  - PR21.155: High Bridge (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1933
    - Perspective study. graphite on board. (Object PR21.155.O1)
    - Perspective study. charcoal on paper, 1933 May (Object PR21.155.O2)
  - PR21.156: Hill Seminary (Saint Paul, Minn.)
    - Rolled drawings (Offsite-box CG-194)
  - PR21.157: J. G. Hill Triumphal Arch (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1893
    - Perspective study. watercolor on paper., 1893 (Object PR21.157.O1)
  - PR21.158: Hodges Nichols Building (Duluth, Minn.)
  - PR21.159: Home Insurance Building
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-194)
  - PR21.160: Hotchkiss School (Lakeville, Conn.), 1918
    - Sketch for garden. watercolor on board., 1927 August 2 (Object PR21.160.O1)
    - Sketch for summer house. Colored pencil and watercolor on paper and board., 1927 August 21 (Object PR21.160.O2)
    - Sketch from green looking toward dormitories. watercolor on paper and board., 1927 August 2 (Object PR21.160.O3)
    - Study for infirmary, rear elevation. graphite, colored pencil, and watercolor on board., 1927 July 29 (Object PR21.160.O4)
    - Study for hospital. graphite, colored pencil, and ink wash on trace and board, 1920 January 8 (Object PR21.160.O5)
  - PR21.161: Hotchkiss School (Salisbury, Conn.)
  - PR21.162: Hotel St. Louis (Duluth, Minn.), 1902
    - Private dining room (perspective). watercolor on paper. (Object PR21.162.O1)
    - Rolled drawings (Offsite-box CG-3)
  - PR21.163: J. A. Humbird Residence (Mason, Wis.), 1899
  - PR21.164: F. W. Hunter, Elm Street Apartment House (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1884
  - PR21.165: Hurley Hotel (New York, N.Y.), 1914
    - Study for hotel (street perspective). ink on paper and board., 1914 February (Object PR21.165.O1)
      Housed with PR21.347.O8 and PR21.355.O2
  - PR21.166: International Building (New York, N.Y.)
    - Perspective study. colored pencil on board. (Object PR21.166.O1)
  - PR21.167: Interzone Building (New York, N.Y.), 1920
  - PR21.168: Ives Memorial Library (New Haven, Conn.)
    - Exterior perspective study. graphite and watercolor on paper and board. (Object PR21.168.O1)
  - PR21.169: C. D. Jackson Warehouse (Bronx, N.Y.), 1915
    - Two exterior perspective studies. graphite, charcoal, and watercolor on board., 1915 December 31; 1916 (Object PR21.169.O1)
    - Exterior perspective sketch. graphite and charcoal on board. (Object PR21.169.O2)
    - Exterior perspective. graphite and watercolor on board., 1918 July (Object PR21.169.O3)
    - Exterior perspective. watercolor and colored pencil on paper and board., 1918 (Object PR21.169.O4)
  - PR21.170: Jaffrey's Estate (New York, N.Y.), 1899
  - PR21.171: Jamaica Estates (New York, N.Y.), 1908
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-192)
  - PR21.172: James House (Greenwich, Conn.), 1911
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-192)
  - PR21.173: Johnson & Johnson, Industrial Plant and Terminal (New Brunswick, N.J.)
  - PR21.174: Thomas Johnson, Tomb
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-193)
  - PR21.175: Johnson, Hazelett & Co., Storefront (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1888
    - Front elevation study. graphite and watercolor on board. (Object PR21.175.O1)
  - PR21.176: Jusserand Memorial (Washington, D.C.), 1933
    - Study showing elevation and plan. charcoal on paper and board. (Object PR21.176.O1)
  - PR21.177: C. D. Kerr, Store (Saint Cloud, Minn.)
  - PR21.178: Kinney Building (Newark, N.J.), 1915
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-5)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-6)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-7)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-8)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-9)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-10)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-11)
  - PR21.178A: James Lawther Store (Red Wing, Minn.)
    - Rolled drawings (Offsite-box CG-194)
  - PR21.179: Col. Lindsey, Hotel (Thomasville, Ga.)
  - PR21.180: W. H. Lightner House (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1893
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-192)
  - PR21.181: Lincoln House (Waterbury, Conn.)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-12)
  - PR21.182: Livingston Cottage (Indian River, Fla.)
    - Exterior perspective study. watercolor on paper. (Object PR21.182.O1)
  - PR21.183: Long, E. C., House (Saint Paul, Minn.)
    - Front view of residence, Summit Avenue. watercolor on board. (Object PR21.183.O1)
    - View of end of dining room looking toward hall, study for hall settee, elevation and plan of hall table. mixed media on board. (Object PR21.183.O2)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-12)
  - PR21.184: Lord and Taylor Store (New York, N.Y.), 1912
  - PR21.185: Louisiana Purchase Exposition. Palace of Fine Art [Saint Louis Art Museum] (Saint Louis, Mo.), 1904
    - Bird's-eye view of Forest Park from Saint Louis Art Museum. photoreproduction mounted on board., 1916 (Item PR21.185.O1)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-68)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-69)
  - PR21.186: Louisiana Purchase Exposition. Festival Hall (St. Louis, Mo.)
    - View of hall from Grand Basin. photograph on board. (Object PR21.186.O1)
    - Front elevation study. photoreproduction of drawing on board. (Object PR21.186.O2)
    - Study showing Festival Hall, the Cascades, and Grand Basin. mixed media on linen and board. (Object PR21.186.O3)
  - PR21.187: Lyon Cottage, 1896
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-192)
  - PR21.188: Madison High School (Madison, Wis.)
    - Exterior perspective study. ink on board., 1904 (Object PR21.188.O1)
    - Folded/rolled drawings (Offsite-box CG-2)
  - PR21.189: Main Street House (Southampton, N.Y.), 1923
  - PR21.190: Manitoba Apartment House (Manitoba)
    - Exterior perspectives. ink on paper (poor condition, in fragments). (Object PR21.190.O1)
  - PR21.191: Manitou Island Summer Lodge (White Bear Lake, Minn.)
    - Study (exterior perspective). watercolor on board. (Object PR21.191.O1)
  - PR21.192: Mannheimer Memorial, Como Park (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1904
    - Two sketches: plan and elevation. colored pencil on trace and board. (Object PR21.192.O1)
  - PR21.193: Mantel for house on Bridge and State Streets (New York, N.Y.)
    - Study. ink on paper. (Object PR21.193.O1)
  - PR21.194: Market House Building
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-14)
  - PR21.195: Masonic Club and Office Building (New York, N.Y.), 1921
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-38)
  - PR21.196: MacLaren Estate, Apartment and Store Building (3rd Street and Pleasant Avenue, Saint Paul, Minn.)
    - Stores and apartment house (exterior study). ink on board. (Object PR21.196.O1)
  - PR21.197: D. W. McCourt House (Saint Paul, Minn.)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-12)
  - PR21.198: Mechanics Art High School (Saint Paul, Minn.)
  - PR21.199: Memorial Plaza "Monument to the Pioneers" (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1931
    - Study. graphite and colored pencil on board. (Object PR21.199.O1)
  - PR21.200: Mercantile Building (New York, N.Y.), 1925
  - PR21.201: Methodist Episcopal Church (Great Bend, N.Y.), 1912
  - PR21.202: Minneapolis Chamber of Commerce (Minneapolis, Minn.)
  - PR21.203: Minneapolis and St. Louis Railway, Washington Avenue Depot Building (Minneapolis, Minn.), 1891
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-15)
  - PR21.204: Minnesota Boat Club, Pavilion, 1888
  - PR21.205: Minnesota Capitol Group (Saint Paul, Minn.)
    - Bird's-eye view. graphite on paper, 1931 March 1 (Object PR21.205.O1)
  - PR21.206: Minnesota Club Alterations (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1897
    - First and Second floor plans, number one. ink and watercolor on trace and board. (Object PR21.206.O1)
    - First and Second floor plans, number two. ink and watercolor on trace and board. (Object PR21.206.O2)
    - Attic plan, number one. ink and watercolor on trace and board. (Object PR21.206.O3)
    - Attic plan and basement plan, number two. ink and watercolor on trace and board. (Object PR21.206.O4)
  - PR21.207: Minnesota Historical Society Building (Saint Paul, Minn.)
  - PR21.208: Minnesota Monument (Vicksburg, Minn.), 1906
    - Design for Minnesota Monument at Vicksburg [front and side elevation studies]. graphite and ink wash on paper backed with linen. (Object PR21.208.O1)
  - PR21.209: Minnesota State Capitol (Saint Paul, Minn.)
    - General view, capitol approaches. graphite on trace and board., 1931 (Object PR21.209.O1)
    - Summit Avenue approach, perspective study. colored pencil on trace. (Object PR21.209.O2)
    - Summit Avenue approach, perspective study. graphite on trace and board., 1931 (Object PR21.209.O3)
    - Front elevation sketch with notes. graphite on trace and mat. (Object PR21.209.O4)
    - Decoration in Senate Chamber [Minnesota, Granary of the World mural]. photograph on board. (Object PR21.209.O5)
    - Back view during construction. photograph removed from board. (Object PR21.209.O6)
    - Partial front view during construction. photograph on board. (Object PR21.209.O7)
    - Front view. photograph removed from board. (Object PR21.209.O8)
    - Front view during construction. photograph on board., 1902 September 30 (Object PR21.209.O9)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-15)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-16)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-17)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-18)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-19)
  - PR21.210: Montana Club